## // Joel Herrero **Full Stack Developer**

□ (+34) 650 723 783 / ⋈ joel@elniu.dev ☑ elniu.dev / 🌣 based on Barcelona / o letjoel

About me

Creating websites and applications has been my passion since the early age of 15. I felt the need to better understand the world around me in a humanistic sense, so I studied for a Bachelor of Arts in Psychology and Humanities. Nevertheless, I quickly gravitated towards web development and have created multiple websites, ecommerce platforms, and web applications for over 10 years, particularly within the hospitality industry. This has allowed me to embark on an interesting professional journey that has given me a growth-oriented mindset and a deep understanding of transparent and honest communication. Always eager for knowledge, I have continued to update my technological skills through professional training to improve continuously. I enjoy my great hobby, which fortunately is also my profession.

## **Education**

Barcelona, Spain **Certificate of Higher Education in Interests** Cycle touring. Sept. 2022 - Present **Software Development** Hiking. TBS video games.

IOC (INSTITUT OBERT DE CATALUNYA) Web Application Development (DAW)

Barcelona, Spain **MERN Bootcamp** English C1 (British Council) Languages Oct. 2022 - Apr. 2023 FACTORÍA F5 Spanish.

Full stack developer (850h).

**University Degree in Humanities** Barcelona, Spain Soft skills AIPSW Practitioner ☑ Sep. 2008 - Jun. 2014 UPF (POMPEU FABRA UNIVERSITY) (Public speaking training)

Mention in philosophy.

Skills

✓ HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript

✓ React, Next js, Tailwind, Material UI, Bootstrap, SASS.

✓ Node js, Nest js, Express, Socket.io, Swagger.

√ MongoDB, MySQL

✓ REST API | Authorization | Documentation.

✓ TDD, Jest, Supertest. Git, AGILE, Jira, Clean code.

√ WordPress

**Expertise** 

JavaScript \$\$TypeScript \$\$C# \*\*\* PHP \$\$ Python \*\* Java ☆

Catalan C2.

## **Experience**

## **Library of Things**

WEB DEVELOPER

FREELANCER FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Complex object lending app project for a municipal council. Node js full stack app: React, API with Nest js (Express), TypeScript, MySQL.

Social cooking app. Node js: React, API with Nest js (Express), TypeScript, MongoDB.

La recette social

FREELANCER FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Barcelona, Spain **Elected** 

FREELANCER GAME DEVELOPER Game programming with C# and Unity 3D. Game design (UI, economy balancing).

Málaga, Spain **Hotel PMS** Sep. 2014 - Jul. 2019

Implementation of custom property management & booking system (WordPress based).

Barcelona, Spain Multiple projects 2009 - Sept. 2014

WordPress sites, PHP-SQL applications, E-commerce, ...

Barcelona, Spain

Barcelona, Spain

Feb. 2023 - Apr. 2023

Dec. 2022 - Feb. 2023

Sep. 2021 - Oct. 2022